<Employment>AXA

	<Date>

		<Type>Start date
		<Day>
		<Month>August
		<Year>2000

	</Date>

	<Date>

		<Type>End date
		<Day>
		<Month>November
		<Year>2000

	</Date>

	<Site>London
	<Site>Bristol
	<Site>Paris

	<Role>Business Analyst

	<Summary>

		<001>
			<P>This was a peculiar role.  I was asked by Perot to undertake some business analysis work in conjunction with some other Perot employees.  We were working under the direction of a French consultancy company, for the client, AXA Sun Life.  The structure of AXA Sun Life – head office in France, but with strong local autonomy – meant that the engagement was crippled by political manoeuvrings from the start.
			</P>
		</001>

		<002>
			<P>On assignment with AXA, I worked as a business analyst within a small Perot Systems team in partnership with a French consultancy company.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Summary>

	<Benefit>Technical Responsibility

		<P>My technical responsibility within this assignment was limited to analysis of business requirements.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Supervisory Responsibility

		<P>I had no supervisory responsibilities during this assignment.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Personal Achievements

		<P>My achievements on a personal level during this assignment included working with a multi-national team covering many different companies, and successfully delivering business requirements within this complex mix of people and teams.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Skills Acquired

		<P>This assignment built on my existing communications skills, and business analysis skills.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Detailed_Description>

		<001>

			<P>AXA are one of the world's largest insurance companies, and within Europe wanted to introduce a Europe-wide web based financial portal offering customer's the ability to manage all aspects of their finances on-line; from a simple bank account, through to share purchase.
			</P>

			<P>The bulk of the work was being undertaken by Perot System's French partner company, and Perot Systems were asked to provide a team to be based within the UK to work with AXA Sun-Life in Bristol, to derive UK specific requirements for the portal.  I was a business analyst within the team.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

		<002>

			<P>On assignment with AXA, I worked as a business analyst within a small Perot Systems team in partnership with a French consultancy company.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>June
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>July
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2003
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2006
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Detailed_Description>

</Employment>
