<Employment>KPN Mobiel

	<Date>

		<Type>Start date
		<Day>
		<Month>April
		<Year>2000

	</Date>

	<Date>

		<Type>End date
		<Day>
		<Month>July
		<Year>2000

	</Date>

	<Site>Groningen, Netherlands

	<Role>Project Manager

	<Summary>

		<001>
			<P>In January, 2000 – as a contractor working for Perot Systems – I had travelled to the Netherlands to help prepare the bid documentation for this major contract for Perot Systems.  When I joined Perot Systems as a permanent employee in April, 2000 my first project was managing this development effort which was an integral part of the overall programme between KPN Mobiel and Perot Systems.
			</P>

			<P>In July 2000, KPN Mobiel and Perot Systems formed a new joint venture company.
			</P>
		</001>

		<002>
			<P>For this assignment, I was based in the Netherlands on the delivery of a major new customer relationship management (CRM) programme.  This was a major business change programme into an existing, conservative organisation.
			</P>

			<P>I project managed a team made up of permanent KPN employees, contractors, Perot employees and third party employees, using new technology to deliver a 'proof of viability' system for the proposed new systems.  The 'proof of viability' was delivered and presented to the board for approval for progression to the main development.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Summary>

	<Benefit>Technical Responsibility

		<P>As project manager, all technical responsibility for this project rested with me.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Supervisory Responsibility

		<P>My supervisory responsibility during this assignment was as project manager for a team of ten people from within Perot Systems, KPN, and the third party supplier of the applications software tool-kit.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Personal Achievements

		<P>This assignment provided me with the opportunity to achieve a successful project in a different European country with a team of people from different companies all with differing aims.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Skills Acquired

		<P>This assignment built on my project management skills, and my communications skills, as well as giving me exposure to technologies for application development which I had not previously encountered.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Detailed_Description>

		<001>

			<P>KPN are the Dutch national telecommunications provider, and KPN Mobiel is the division of KPN which handles mobile telephony.  Perot Systems had an alliance with a software delivery department of KPN and were looking to consolidate this relationship with a view to a possible future joint venture partnership.
			</P>

			<P>This assignment was as a direct result of the pre-sales proposal which I had been involved in immediately prior to this assignment.
			</P>

			<P>The overall programme of work was to implement systems which would provide KPN Mobiel with a much better view of, and a much closer relationship with, its customers.
			</P>

			<P>I was asked to project manage a 'proof of viability' project to establish for senior KPN Mobiel management that the solution which had been proposed by KPN's internal architecture group, could actually be made to work.
			</P>

			<P>The project team consisted of ten experienced software developers from within Perot Systems, from KPN Mobiel, and from a third party company who were providing the applications development tools.  The project ran for three months, and successfully delivered a system which demonstrated viability to senior KPN management and which then allowed the overall programme to receive funding.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

		<002>

			<P>During this assignment, I was project manager of a team delivering a 'proof of viability' of a proposed new system, to deliver new customer relationship management systems to KPN Mobiel.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>June
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>July
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2003
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2006
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

		<003>

			<P>For this assignment, I was based in the Netherlands on the delivery of a major new customer relationship management (CRM) programme.  This was a major business change programme into an existing, conservative organisation.
			</P>

			<P>I project managed a team made up of permanent KPN employees, contractors, Perot employees and third party employees, using new technology to deliver a 'proof of viability' system for the proposed new systems.  The 'proof of viability' was delivered and presented to the board for approval for progression to the main development.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>Leadership version
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>July
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Detailed_Description>

</Employment>
