<Employment>Misys Financial Systems

	<Date>

		<Type>Start date
		<Day>
		<Month>February
		<Year>1995

	</Date>

	<Date>

		<Type>End date
		<Day>
		<Month>August
		<Year>1995

	</Date>

	<Site>Worcester, Worcestershire

	<Role>Software Developer

	<Summary>

		<001>
			<P>Misys Financial Systems are a producer of computer systems for the commercial insurance industry. The project that I worked on at Misys - Libra - was a system to assist insurance brokers in the sale of life assurance.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

	</Summary>

	<Benefit>Technical Responsibility

		<P>My technical responsibilities whilst at Misys included being part of a small development and maintenance team, making enhancements and corrections to an existing software product, as well as general 'C', UNIX, RDBMS, SCCS, debugging, Yourdon expertise.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Supervisory Responsibility

		<P>I had no supervisory responsibility whilst at Misys.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Personal Achievements

		<P>Timely delivery of all work assigned to me.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Skills Acquired

		<P>Further building on existing 'C', UNIX, and database (Informix) experience.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Detailed_Description>

		<001>

			<P>I worked at Misys as part of a small team developing and enhancing an existing product for use in the life insurance market.
			</P>

			<P>I was involved in designing the Libra system using the Yourdon design methodology and implementation of the system on a SCO-UNIX platform running an Informix relational database, using 'C' as the development language. The development environment was both SCO-UNIX and DEC Alpha machines using the OSF version of UNIX.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

		<002>

			<P>The project that I worked on at Misys – Libra - was a system to assist insurance brokers in the sale of life assurance.  I was involved in designing the Libra system using the Yourdon design methodology and implementation of the system on a SCO-UNIX platform running an Informix relational database, using 'C' as the development language.  The development environment was both SCO-UNIX and DEC Alpha machines using the OSF version of UNIX.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>January
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>February
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

		<003>

			<P>Misys Financial Systems are a producer of computer systems for the commercial insurance industry.  The project that I worked on at Misys - Libra - was a system to assist insurance brokers in the sale of life assurance.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>June
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>July
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2003
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Type>
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2006
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</003>

	</Detailed_Description>

</Employment>
