<Employment>Perot Systems Europe

	<Date>

		<Type>Start date
		<Day>
		<Month>April
		<Year>2000

	</Date>

	<Date>

		<Type>End date
		<Day>
		<Month>December
		<Year>2001

	</Date>

	<Site>Oakwood Court, Nottingham

	<Role>Project Manager

	<Summary>

		<001>
			<P>My involvement with Perot Systems began in May 1998 and I stayed as a contractor for 18 months.  After a two month break, I returned (January, 2000) to begin a six month contract, but during that time I transferred to being a permanent employee (in April 2000) and I stayed with Perot as a permanent employee for a further 18 months, until December, 2001.
			</P>

			<P>This document refers to my time with Perot Systems as a permanent employee – between April 2000 and December, 2001.
			</P>

		</001>

		<002>
			<P>As a permanent employee of Perot Systems I worked mainly on account-based assignments but also worked on some pre-sales proposals.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Summary>

	<Benefit>Technical Responsibility

		<P>My technical responsibilities during my time with Perot Systems are detailed within the sections relating to the assignments that I undertook for Perot Systems.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Supervisory Responsibility

		<P>I had different supervisory responsibilities for each of the assignments that I worked on whilst at Perot Systems, as detailed in each of the separate sections.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Personal Achievements

		<P>On a personal level, working with Perot Systems allowed me to achieve many of the goals that I had previously set for myself, including managing difficult projects to successful completion, and working in a variety of technical, business and national cultures.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Skills Acquired

		<P>The skills that I acquired whilst working for Perot Systems are detailed in the sections relating to the assignments, below.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Detailed_Description>

		<001>

			<P>Perot Systems are a world-wide IT services company, who undertake programmes and projects on behalf of clients.  When I started work with Perot Systems as an employee, it was after having already worked with Perot as a contractor for more than a year (see other sections).
			</P>

			<P>The accounts and assignments that I worked on are detailed in other documents.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

		<002>

			<P>As a permanent employee of Perot Systems I worked mainly on account-based assignments but also worked on some pre-sales proposals.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>June
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>July
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2003
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

		<003>

			<P>Having already worked as a freelance IT contractor with Perot Systems, I joined in January 2000. As a permanent employee of Perot Systems I worked mainly on account-based assignments but also worked on some pre-sales proposals.
			</P>

			<P>Assignments whilst at Perot Systems were as follows :
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2006
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</003>

	</Detailed_Description>

</Employment>
