<Employment>Rathlin Software Limited

	<Date>

		<Type>Start date
		<Day>
		<Month>January
		<Year>1993

	</Date>

	<Date>

		<Type>End date
		<Day>
		<Month>April
		<Year>2000

	</Date>

	<Site>

	<Role>IT Contractor

	<Summary>

		<001>
			<P>Rathlin Software Limited was the company that I set up in order to allow me to work as an IT contractor.
			</P>
		</001>

		<002>
			<P>This period of time covers all of the contracts that are listed below, from my first with Barclays Network Services starting in January 1993, to the last with Perot Systems ending in April 2000.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Summary>

	<Benefit>Technical Responsibility

		<P>My technical responsibilities are given in each section.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Supervisory Responsibility

		<P>I had no internal supervisory responsibility whilst at Rathlin Software - all of my supervisory responsibility during this time, came whilst working as a contractor for the various companies detailed below.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Personal Achievements

		<P>Working for over seven years as a contractor, gave me many personal achievements.  In addition to the specific achievements listed within each section, simply being a contractor, allowed me visibility of many and various companies, and showed me that I could adapt rapidly and well to various working environments and a variety of people.  This period also gave me the basics of the skills required to run a small business.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Skills Acquired

		<P>As detailed in each section.
		</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Detailed_Description>

		<001>

			<P>The detail of the contract engagements that I undertook as part of Rathlin Software Limited are detailed in the relevant files.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

		<002>

			<P>I worked as a freelance IT contractor on many assignments during this period of time.  The main assignments are detailed in the relevant files.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>July
					<Year>2002
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2003
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>September
					<Year>2006
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

	</Detailed_Description>

</Employment>
