<Employment>Unisys

	<Date>

		<Type>Start date
		<Day>
		<Month>August
		<Year>1986

	</Date>

	<Date>

		<Type>End date
		<Day>
		<Month>August
		<Year>1987

	</Date>

	<Site>Petticoat Lane, London

	<Role>Industrial Trainee

	<Summary>

		<001>
			<P>Industrial placement during my third year of my undergraduate degree course.
			</P>
		</001>

		<002>
			<P>During my second year at University, we were offered the opportunity to take a year's placement in industry.  I took the opportunity, and worked for Unisys (at the time that I started it was actually Burroughs) in London for a year.  The office that I was based at was in Middlesex Street next door to Liverpool Street train station. The work that I was involced in was mainly to do with the retail banking sector, and placing small personal computer units within that environment.
			</P>
		</002>

		<003>
			<P>At Unisys I was employed as an industrial trainee on a year's placement from University which gave me an excellent insight into the commercial IT industry.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</003>

	</Summary>

	<Benefit>Technical Responsibility

		<P>I was part of the Office Automation team, with responsibility for constructing solutions for a variety of clients.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Supervisory Responsibility

		<P>I had no supervisory responsibility whilst at Unisys.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Personal Achievements

		<P>My major personal achievement whilst at Unisys was leading a training course for a major high street bank.
		</P>
			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Benefit>Skills Acquired

		<P>Unisys product range - B20 workstations and BTOS operating system.</P>
		<P>General commercial experience.</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

	</Benefit>

	<Detailed_Description>

		<001>

			<P>My industrial placement year at Unisys was the third year of my four year sandwich degree course.
			</P>

			<P>The year's placement gave me my first insight into the 'real' world of work and commercial realities.
			</P>

			<P>The intention of the year was to get involved in a broad variety of projects to give an overview of the IT industry in general.
			</P>

			<P>The department of Unisys that I was involved in was the 'Office Automation' department, whose responsibilities covered basic networked personal computers, running word processing and spreadsheet packages, right through to large document processing machines used by high volume cheque processing departments, typically of banks. As such, the department had many clients within the City of London.
			</P>

			<P>I worked with more senior full-time employees of the company - and occasionally on my own - implementing office automation solutions. During my time at Unisys, I ran a course on the use of a bespoke banking software system for the staff of a major high street bank.
			</P>

			<Used>BCS application
				<Date>
					<Type>Application date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</001>

		<002>

			<P>At Unisys I was employed as an industrial trainee on a year's placement from University. My job involved liaison with customers and implementing office automation solutions. During my time at Unisys I ran a course on the use of a bespoke banking software system for the staff of a major high street bank. I also attended several training courses relating to the computer systems that are sold by Unisys.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>May
					<Year>1998
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>March
					<Year>1999
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>1999
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</002>

		<003>

			<P>At Unisys I was employed as an industrial trainee on a year's placement from University which gave me an excellent insight into the commercial IT industry.
			</P>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>June
					<Year>1999
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>August
					<Year>1999
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>February
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

			<Used>Curriculum Vitae
				<Date>
					<Type>CV date
					<Day>
					<Month>April
					<Year>2000
				</Date>
			</Used>

		</003>

	</Detailed_Description>

</Employment>
